# Alexandra Hernandez

San Diego, California 92126 (951) 595-9228

alexavndrarh@gmail.com, arh003@ucsd.edu alexavndra.github.io

UC San Diego undergraduate with experience in programming, development, and design. Majoring in Cognitive Sciences (Machine Learning and Neural Computation) and minoring in Computer Sciences. Worked on projects involving Spotify API, website design, and prototype testing/implementation.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### UC San Diego Cognitive Sciences Department

COGS1 Instructional Assistant

La Jolla, CA

Jan 2023-Present

Work alongside Professor Mary ET Boyle in Introduction to Cognitive Sciences. Responsibilities include creating section assignments and quiz questions, as well as leading two discussion sections. Also managed class communications and the IA/TA Google application

## Qualcomm Institute UC San Diego

WordPress Developer

La Jolla, CA

Sept 2022-

Present

Work on UI/UX, website design and consultation for Qualcomm Institute's TREDS Program. Using LMS applications, Figma, Google Cloud API, HTML, and CSS, as well as WordPress and PHP. Help implement digital programs, and collect and analyze data and research for supervisors. Work with SEO concept and tools for main website.

WalkMe UC San Diego

La Jolla, CA

May 2022-Sept 2022

Worked on frontend design, analytics, and implementation for WalkMe program at UC San Diego. Used jQuery, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and CMS. Implementing designs for university websites and programs. Prototyped and tested content implementations for UC San Diego. Used JIRA and HTTPS for managing software implementation. Utilized automation implementations with content via WalkMe and DAP. In compliance with 508 accessibilities.

#### **EDUCATION**

Data Analyst

UC SAN DIEGO La Jolla, CA

Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Sciences (specializing in Machine Learning & Neural Computation). Minoring in Computer Science

September 2021–Present

Honors: Marshall College Provost Honors (FA21, WI22, SP22, FA22).

La Jolla, CA Introductory program for CSE, CE, ECE, Data Science, and Cognitive Science majors offered by UC July 2021-September 2021

San Diego. Gained experience in Python, HTML, CSS, and efficient problem solving. Created a program with Spotify API at the end of the course (see Projects).

## **SKILLS**

Experience in Java, Python, MATLAB and Git, with usage of VSCode, GitHub, NetBeans, Atom, Jupyter Notebook, and React. Basic SOL, Google Cloud API, and HTTPS/XML knowledge. Previous usage/experience of JIRA (IBM Toolchain Build Tool).

Proficiency in web designing with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and Content Management Systems.

Proficiency in Graphic Design, especially UI/UX and web design. Worked with user feedback programs.

High experience in design programs such as Figma and Adobe Illustrator; Basic knowledge of Sketch.

#### **PROJECTS**

Astrologify: Console app that uses Spotify API, Python, and Git to create user playlist with given user data. Used VSCode and GitHub.

Reminder App: Desktop program that uses EasyApp UI and Java to create reminders for the user through tasks and lists; incorporates times and dates. Created using NetBeans IDE.

### REFERENCES

Francisco Mejia (WalkMe): f4mejia@ucsd.edu

Lesley Copeland (Qualcomm Institute): lcopeland@health.ucsd.edu